A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of the Vice President of Administration, Office Files of Arthur D. Trottenberg FA669
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Real Estate, 1966-1979; 1967-1976; X
  - United Nations Development Corporation (U.N.D.C.)
    - Development of U.N. Area, 1968 January-March (Box 58, Folder 563)
    - Development of U.N. Area, 1968 April-June (Box 58, Folder 564)
    - Bills, Bylaws, and Reports, etc., 1968-1971 (Box 58, Folder 565)
    - Hammer, Greene, Siler Associates, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 566)
    - U.N.D.C. Board of Directors, 1968-1971 (Box 58, Folder 567)
    - U.N.D.C. Board of Directors, meeting, 1969 January 30 (Box 58, Folder 568)
    - U.N.D.C. Board of Directors, meeting, 1969 May 12 (Box 58, Folder 569)
    - U.N.D.C. Board of Directors, meeting, 1969 August 4 (Box 58, Folder 570)
    - U.N.D.C. Board of Directors, meeting, 1969 August 18 (Box 58, Folder 571)
    - U.N.D.C. Board of Directors, meeting, 1969 October 30 (Box 58, Folder 572)
    - U.N.D.C. Clippings and Charts, 1968-1971 (Box 59, Folder 573)
    - Transfer of Real Estate to U.N.D.C., 1971 (Box 59, Folder 574)
    - Fund for Area Planning and Development Grants, 1968-1971 (Box 59, Folder 575)
    - U.N.D.C. – Recoverable Grant, 1979 (Box 59, Folder 576)
    - Beaux Arts Hotel, 1968 (Box 59, Folder 577)
    - The Eye Cinema, 1968-1969 (Box 59, Folder 578)
    - John H. Muller, Real Estate Consultant, 1967 (Box 59, Folder 579)
- Board of Trustees, 1962-1979; 1967-1978; XI
  Board of Trustees The Board of Trustees series primarily contains information on Board meetings ranging from 1967 to 1979. It also includes the Executive Committee and the Finance Committee meetings from this time. These folders contain materials such as Minutes from the meetings, as well as reports to be discussed at the meetings and press releases announcing decisions solidified at the meetings. Dockets and Treasurer's Reports, however, have been removed from the folders; thus, this series is best used in conjunction with the Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, and Finance Committee Records. In addition to the various meetings, the series contains information on (topics in general folders), as well as correspondence with some of the Board's members, such as Julius A. Stratton, Alexander Heard, and Walter Haas. Particularly interesting is a folder about Henry Ford II's resignation from the Board of Trustees. As the son and grandson of the two Fords that established the Foundation in 1936, Henry II had a personal connection to the Foundation, as well as a respect for the Foundation's work. After 33 years as a trustee, Ford was the longest-standing Board member at the time of his resignation in 1977. Ford served the Foundation from its early, informal beginnings and helped transition it to its more structured state when the Foundation became a national and international philanthropy in 1950. Ford's letter of resignation left the Foundation with some of his criticisms of how things were being run, attracting a host of negative media coverage, some of which is included in the collection.
  The series consists of memoranda, correspondence, telegrams, reports, policy papers, press releases, newspaper articles, and notes.
  Some materials, such as Minutes from the meetings, Dockets, and Financial Reports, have been removed from the collection and can be found within their respective collections (see Appendix D).
  Series XI, Board of Trustees, is divided into two subseries: General and Meetings. The General subseries contains assorted information about the Board of Trustees and some of its members, including information on Henry Ford's resignation from the Board. The Meetings subseries is divided by regular Board of Trustees meetings, Executive Committee meetings, and Finance Committee meetings, with meetings arranged chronologically. Items within folders are arranged chronologically, maintaining original order.
  - General
    - Board of Trustees, general, 1962-1964 (Box 59, Folder 580)
    - Board of Trustees, general, 1965 (Box 59, Folder 581)
    - Board of Trustees, general, 1966 (Box 59, Folder 582)
    - Board of Trustees, general, 1967 (Box 59, Folder 583)
    - Board of Trustees, general, 1968-1969 (Box 59, Folder 584)
    - Board of Trustees, general, 1970-1971 (Box 59, Folder 585)
    - Board of Trustees, general, 1972-1973 (Box 59, Folder 586)
    - Board of Trustees, general, 1974 January-June (Box 60, Folder 587)
    - Board of Trustees, general, 1974 July-December (Box 60, Folder 588)
    - Board of Trustees, general, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 589)
    - Board of Trustees, general, 1976-1977 (Box 60, Folder 590)
    - Stratton, Julius A., 1965-1969 (Box 60, Folder 591)
    - Heard, Alexander, 1969-1977 (Box 60, Folder 592)
    - Haas, Walter, 1976-1977 (Box 60, Folder 593)
    - Ford, Henry, 1977-1978 (Box 60, Folder 594)
  - Meetings
    - Trustees Meeting, 1967 March (Box 60, Folder 595)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1968 June (Box 60, Folder 596)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1968 September (Box 60, Folder 597)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1968 December (Box 60, Folder 598)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1969 March (Box 60, Folder 599)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1969 June (Box 60, Folder 600)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1969 September (Box 60, Folder 601)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1969 December (Box 61, Folder 602)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1970 March (Box 61, Folder 603)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1970 June (Box 61, Folder 604)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1970 September (Box 61, Folder 605)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1970 December (Box 61, Folder 606)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1971 March (Box 61, Folder 607)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1971 June (Box 61, Folder 608)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1971 September (Box 61, Folder 609)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1971 December (Box 61, Folder 610)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1977 March (Box 61, Folder 611)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1977 June (Box 61, Folder 612)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1977 September (Box 61, Folder 613)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1978 March (Box 61, Folder 614)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1978 June (Box 61, Folder 615)
    - Trustees Meeting, India, 1978 October (Box 61, Folder 616)
    - Trustees Meeting, 1978 December (Box 61, Folder 617)
    - Future Planning Project, 1975 (Box 62, Folder 618)
    - Future Planning Project, 1976 January-September (Box 62, Folder 619)
    - Future Planning Project, 1976 October (Box 62, Folder 620)
    - Future Planning Project, 1977 (Box 62, Folder 621)
    - Executive Committee, 1969-1974 (Box 62, Folder 622)
    - Executive Committee, 1975-1977 (Box 62, Folder 623)
    - Executive Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 62, Folder 624)
    - Finance Committee, 1969 (Box 62, Folder 625)
    - Finance Committee, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 626)
    - Finance Committee, 1971 March, June (Box 62, Folder 627)
    - Finance Committee, 1971 November (Box 62, Folder 628)
    - Finance Committee, 1971 September, December (Box 62, Folder 629)
    - Finance Committee, 1972 March (Box 63, Folder 630)
    - Finance Committee, 1972 June (Box 63, Folder 631)
    - Finance Committee, 1972 September (Box 63, Folder 632)
    - Finance Committee, 1972 December (Box 63, Folder 633)
    - Finance Committee, 1973 March (Box 63, Folder 634)
    - Finance Committee, 1973 June (Box 63, Folder 635)
    - Finance Committee, 1973 September (Box 63, Folder 636)
    - Finance Committee, 1973 December (Box 63, Folder 637)
    - Finance Committee, 1974 March (Box 63, Folder 638)
    - Finance Committee, 1974 June (Box 63, Folder 639)
    - Finance Committee, 1974 September (Box 64, Folder 640)
    - Finance Committee, 1974 December (Box 64, Folder 641)
    - Finance Committee, 1975 March (Box 64, Folder 642)
    - Finance Committee, 1975 June (Box 64, Folder 643)
    - Finance Committee, 1975 September (Box 64, Folder 644)
    - Finance Committee, 1975 December (Box 64, Folder 645)
    - Finance Committee, 1976 March (Box 64, Folder 646)
    - Finance Committee, 1978 March (Box 64, Folder 647)
    - Finance Committee, 1978 June (Box 64, Folder 648)
    - Finance Committee, 1978 October, December (Box 64, Folder 649)
    - Finance Committee, 1979 March (Box 64, Folder 650)
    - Finance Committee, 1979 June (Box 64, Folder 651)
- Appendix D: Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, and Finance Committee Papers Removed from Collection
  Appendix D: Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, and Finance Committee Papers
  BOARD OF TRUSTEES Note: Agendas, Minutes, and Dockets for the following meeting dates have been removed from the collection and can be found in the Board of Trustees Records. However, some folders in the collection still contain Agendas and Minutes; only those Agendas and Minutes that were already filed with the Dockets in the Board of Trustees Records have been removed from the collection.
  March 1972 June 1972 September 1972 December 1972 March 29-30, 1973 June 28-29, 1973 September 1973 December 1973 March 1974 June 1974 September 1974 December 1974 March 1975 June 1975 September 1975 December 1975 March 1976 June 1976 September 1976 December 1976 March 24-25, 1977 June 23-24, 1977 September 29-30, 1977 December 7-8, 1977 March 30-31, 1978 June 29-30, 1978 October 5-6, 1978 December 7-8, 1978
  EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE Note: Minutes for the following meeting dates have been removed from the collection and can be found in the Executive Committee Records.
  February 24, 1970 May 28, 1970 November 6, 1970 February 2, 1971 April 30, 1971 November 16, 1971 February 23, 1972 October 18, 1972 December 8, 1972 February 7, 1973 October 31, 1973 February 6, 1974 October 30, 1974 February 26, 1975 May 22, 1975 October 29, 1975 February 27, 1976 November 3, 1976 February 16, 1977 May 23, 1977
  FINANCE COMMITTEE Note: Minutes, Treasurer's Reports, and Financial Reports for the following meeting dates have been removed from the collection and can be found in the Finance Committee Records.
  March 26, 1969 March 24, 1971 June 23, 1971 September 22, 1971 December 9, 1971 March 29, 1972 June 28, 1972 September 27, 1972 December 8, 1972 March 28, 1973 June 27, 1973 September 24, 1973 December 13, 1973 March 27, 1974 June 26, 1974 September 26, 1974 December 12, 1974 March 25, 1975 June 26, 1975 September 24, 1975 December 11, 1975 February 27, 1976 March 24, 1976 September 22, 1976 December 9, 1976 March 23, 1977 December 7, 1977 March 29, 1978 June 1978 October 5-6, 1978 December 6, 1978 March 28, 1979 June 27, 1979
- Appendix E: Program-Related Investments Removed from Collection
  Appendix E: Program-Related Investments
  Note: The following companies are recipients of program-related investments. Folders containing information on these PRIs have been removed from the collection. Information on these PRIs was originally located within the Closed Grant File Room at Ford Foundation.
  Acadian Delight ACTION All Pro Chicken, Inc. Cable TV – Broadcasting Center for Understanding Media, Inc. Cheetah Tours Coalition Venture Corporation Community Progress, Inc. Congaree Iron and Steel Cooperative Services, Inc. Daily Made (Ship Shape) Detroit Educational Television Foundation East Central Catfish Ebony Development Corporation Educational Broadcasting Corporation WNET/Ch. 13 Federation of Southern Cooperatives Feedinco First Harlem Securities Corporation Fort Lincoln Development Corporation Freedom Enterprises Funds for Self Enterprise (Cincinnati Business Assistance and Determined Young Men) The Growing Mind Harvard Community Health Plan India (Bombay) Soybean Processing Plant Jefferson County Improvement Corporation Mecco Enterprises, Inc. MESBIC (Minority Enterprise Small Business Investment Companies) Mobilization for Youth Mortgage Opportunities, Inc. National Council on Crime and Delinquency National Housing Partnership The Nature Conservancy New Breed Industries North Milwaukee State Bank Our Markets, Inc. Progress Enterprises (Zion Enterprises) Rhode Island Group Health Association The Salk Institute Shaw University The Third Press Vic-Way Broadcasting Corporation W.V.B. Corporation Yale College
- Appendix F: Legal Consultants Removed from Collection
  Appendix F: Legal Consultants
  Note: The following lists the legal consultants used by the Foundation. Some of these firms can still be found within the collection, primarily in the form of correspondence or consultant reports. Evidence of the usage of other firms has been wholly removed from the collection because the materials were non-archival. The following is a complete list of all legal consultants that were, at one point, present in Trottenberg's collection.
  Altheimer and Gray Cravath, Swaine, and Moore Debevoise, Plimpton, Lyons, and Gates Ferguson and Capron Ginsburg, Feldman, and Bress Hill, Lewis, Adams, Goodrich, and Tait McCoy, Weaver, Wiggins, Cleveland, and Raper Morgan, Lewis, and Bockius Patterson, Belknap, and Webb Pillsbury, Madison, and Sutro Shearman and Sterling